

COLLEGE PARK MD, USA

🛮 +1 2408257455 | 🔀 bansal01@umd.edu | 🄏 arpitbansal297.github.io | 🖸 github.com/arpitbansal297

Research Interests _____

My broad research interest lies in improving the understanding of Deep Neural Networks empirically and hence improving its training and inference. My research work ranges from algorithmic synthesis with neural networks to watermarking neural networks to investigating neural network's behaviors. Currently, I am understanding the mechanisms behind the working of diffusion models and thus improving them for different AI generation tasks.

Education

University of Maryland, College Park

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (4.0/4.0)

- Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein
- Dean's Fellowship

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

BACHELORS + MASTERS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

- Minor in Computer Science
- Advisor: Prof. Rajiv Ranjan Sahay

College Park Jan 2021 - present

Kharaqpur, India

Aug 2014 - May 2019

Industry Experience _____

July 2019 - Dec 2020 Software Developer, Visa Incorporated, India
May 2018 - July 2018 Software Developer Intern, Visa Incorporated, India

May 2017 - July 2017 Software Developer Intern, Fission Labs, India

Publications

End-to-end Algorithm Synthesis with Recurrent Networks: Logical Extrapolation Without Overthinking

A. Bansal*, A. Schwarzchild*, E. Borgnia, Z. Emam, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (Neurips) 2022*

Certified Neural Network Watermarks with Randomized Smoothing

A. Bansal*, P. Yeh Chiang*, M. Curry, R. Jain, C. Wigington, V. Manjunatha, J. P Dickerson, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML - Spotlight) 2022*

Can You Learn the Same Model Twice? Investigating Reproducibility and Double Descent from the Decision Boundary Perspective

G. Somepalli, L. Fowl, **A. Bansal**, P. Yeh Chiang, Y. Dar, R. Baraniuk, M.GoldBlum, T. Goldstein *Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR - Oral) 2022*

Preprints _____

Cold Diffusion: Inverting Arbitrary Image Transforms Without Noise

A. Bansal, E. Borgnia, H. Chu, J Li, H. Kazemi, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein

MetaBalance: High-Performance Neural Networks for Class-Imbalanced Data

A. Bansal, M. Goldblum, V. Cherepanova, A. Schwarzschild, C Bayan Bruss, T. Goldstein

Datasets for studying generalization from easy to hard examples

A. Schwarzschild, E. Borgnia, A. Gupta, A. Bansal, Z. Emam, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein

Preventing unauthorized use of proprietary data: Poisoning for secure dataset release

L. Fowl, P. yeh Chiang, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, A. Bansal, W. Czaja, T. Goldstein

Pag-net: Progressive attention guided depth super-resolution network

A. Bansal, S. Jonna, R. R Sahay

Teaching Experience _

Fall 2021 **Control Systems**, Teaching Assistant Spring 2021 **Operating Systems**, Teaching Assistant

University of Maryland, College Park University of Maryland, College Park

Relevant Course-work_

Machine Learning Information Retrieval (IIT), Machine Learning (IIT), Speech and NLP (IIT), Deep Learning

(UMD) Algorithms in Machine Learning (UMD)

Signal Processing Digital Signal Processing (IIT), Statistical Signal Processing (IIT), Probability and Stochastic

Processes (IIT), Random Processes (UMD), Information Theory (UMD), Numerical Analysis I

(UMD), Advanced Numerical Optimization (UMD)